make

allows you to have a program with multiple files, and recompile the files that have been changed since the last make


TARGET : PREREQUISITES
TAB -> RULE

ex:
rule_b : rule_a
	echo "rule B"

-	c files
-	header files
-	object files
-	library files

clean:
	rm *.o








ar rc

ar		= creates and maintains library archives

r		= replace or add specified files to the library

c		= silent option, does not display the standard error

ranlib	= add or update the table of contents of archive libraries